<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>schoolbellsinc</title>
    <link>http://schoolbellsinc.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on schoolbellsinc</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <managingEditor>yourname@example.com (yourname)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>yourname@example.com (yourname)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2015 School Bells, Inc.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 16:35:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://schoolbellsinc.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>firstpost</title>
      <link>http://schoolbellsinc.github.io/2016/08/25/firstpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 16:35:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yourname@example.com (yourname)</author>
      <guid>http://schoolbellsinc.github.io/2016/08/25/firstpost/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Education&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Belizean Educational System is based on British and Caribbean Models which divide schools into Primary, Secondary and Tertiary tiers. Children begin their eight years of primary education with two years of &amp;laquo;Infant&amp;raquo; classes, followed by six &amp;laquo;standards&amp;raquo;. Secondary education is divided into four &amp;laquo;forms&amp;raquo;. The sixth form of 2 years is the equivalent to Junior Colleges (Sixth Form) that provide post-secondary diplomas recognized in most American and Caribbean institutions of higher learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The majority of schools are public and funded by both the Belizean Government and The Roman Catholic Church. Belize&amp;rsquo;s existing literacy rate is about 75 to 90 percent with an approximate fifty percent secondary dropout rate especially in the Toledo District.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the Educational Act of 2000 made primary education compulsory for children five to nine years of age, the mandate is not strictly enforced. In addition, nearly three out of five high school aged children are not enrolled in school at this time. Read More
EDUCATIONAL NEEDS:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are always in need of volunteers and financial donations to help make a difference. Won&amp;rsquo;t you help?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whiteboards, bookshelves, books, computers, printers, book bags&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overhead projectors, furniture, minor repairs, painting, toilets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TV, copier, educational software, radio to warn them of hurricane&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adult Summer Literacy Program/ Children&amp;rsquo;s Summer Projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sponsors to sponsor a child&amp;rsquo;s school fees, text books, or uniforms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Donations of children&amp;rsquo;s books, library books, basic school supplies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>http://schoolbellsinc.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 16:35:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yourname@example.com (yourname)</author>
      <guid>http://schoolbellsinc.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;School Bells, Inc, a 501&amp;copy; 3 non-profit humanitarian organization was founded in 2003 with the mission to serve and provide essential life skills, educational support, economic growth, and health services for underserved communities. School Bells, Inc. accomplishes these goals through a variety of programs geared toward uplifting communities. School Bells, Inc. is dedicated to providing educational and medical services to Belize and her many villages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are children with worms and skin disease, who are malnourished. Children are going to school without a breakfast or lunch. Many adults and children have significant tooth decay. School Bells, Inc. is committed in helping these families and children in education and health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The organization is set up to function with volunteers, donations, fundraisers, supporters, and partners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The funds will not be diverted into administration salaries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All funds will benefit those who we serve through the School Bells, Inc. projects. Our goal is to bring positive changes to impoverished families through our educational and healthcare programs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>home</title>
      <link>http://schoolbellsinc.github.io/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 16:35:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yourname@example.com (yourname)</author>
      <guid>http://schoolbellsinc.github.io/home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How You Can Help
Give: Our greatest need is an operating budget! We want to purchase a van to transport medicines and medical equipment around the country. In addition, we need to cover $2500 shipping costs for donated materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What your money can do &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$2000 brings electricity to a rural school
$350 allows a family to send their child to high school
$40 supports a student in elementary school for a year
$20 puts a blood sugar test in a diabetic hand
$300 places a laptop in a school
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you select one of the above options,100% of your donation will go to that choice. General donations will go towards paying for the annual shipment of goods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fill out the sign-up form to get involved&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volunteer: School Bells sponsors medical and educational trips each year. Trips vary in length from 7 to 12 days and offer the opportunity to SERVE in the most underserved communities and schools. We are looking for teachers, dentists, general practitioners, OB/GYNs, nurses, pediatricians, and generally nice people who want to be a part of this experience. We WILL find a role that is right for you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fill out the sign-up form to get involved&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collect and donate: School Bells annually ships a ConEx container to Belize. We want to fill it with the most needed supplies for schools: computers, books, construction paper, pens and pencils, markers, glue, poster paper, teaching manipulatives and support materials. Conduct a drive at your school or business. Contact us and we will pick up for shipment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fill out the sign-up form to get involved&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sponsor:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Tuition for a child to go to school for a year is $40/child for elementary school and $250/child for secondary.
Send a care package with uniforms, school supplies, small toys/learning manipulatives, new shoes, etc.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>